# Jenny Kim

New York, NY | 201-294-0328 | jennykimdev@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Blog

### FRONT END DEVELOPER

As a business graduate from Carnegie Mellon University turned front end developer, I use organization and time management to create thoughtfully planned out applications with JavaScript and React. With an interest and tact for design, I have a passion in creating aesthetic UIs for an enhanced experience, frequently wireframing prior to programming to ensure the end product matches the initial vision. I deliver timely results with my detail-oriented work ethic. I also speak three languages, which gives me strong cross-cultural communication amongst teams and with clients.

#### **SKILLS**

Technical: JavaScript, ReactJS, ReduxJS, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Material UI (MUI), Figma, Wireframing, Ruby on

Rails, REST API, SQLite, PostgreSQL, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify

Language: Korean (fluent), Japanese (conversational)

### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

my travelogue - Github Backend, Frontend | Video Demo

Single-page application (SPA) for users to log and track their past/upcoming trips, equipped with a D-day counter

- Backend created with Rails API. Active Record. PostgreSQL, and Active Model Serializers
- Frontend created with JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, MUI, and date-fns
- Utilized React-Router to create 3 client-side routes; React-Modal for forms and showing itineraries; and Redux-Thunk to communicate asynchronously between backend and frontend
- Implemented JWT and localStorage on the client-side, bcrypt on the server-side to ensure secure user authentication

## Tableau d'Ambiance - Github Backend, Frontend | Video Demo | Deployed Web App

Picture board SPA, where users can create albums and upload photos

- Frontend created with vanilla JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Configured Active Storage to communicate with Amazon S3 cloud storage for image uploading
- Utilized fetch for backend and frontend to communicate and process requests asynchronously

## Pilim - Github | Video Demo | Deployed Web App

Web app for casual movie viewers to create movie lists and review movies all in one place

- Created with Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, SQLite, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Rendered frontend with erb (Embedded RuBy) to output pure HTML
- Approached planning with applying a UI/UX design thinking process by creating user stories
- Implemented OmniAuth for Facebook and Google for users to login/signup more easily, along with the bcrypt gem

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**MEK Review** Palisades Park, NJ

Jr. Counselor of Enrollment and Engagement

06/2020 - 06/2021

- Assisted with various administrative tasks for a local SAT prep school to ensure smooth operations, including registration and billing
- Provided consultations to new/existing students to appropriate programs, communicating with parents and troubleshooting any issues along the way

**Japan Society** New York, NY 06/2019 - 08/2019

Human Resources Intern

- Migrated 100+ employee records from paper to digital and updated reimbursement records, working alongside Finance department to ensure timely delivery of checks
- Maintained job postings on various hiring platforms and initially screened resumes to identify strong candidates

### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** New York, NY 02/2021 - 12/2021

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Carnegie Mellon University

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration: Minor in Japanese Sponsored Study Abroad Program - Temple University | Tokyo, Japan

Pittsburgh, PA Graduated, 05/2020 01/2018 - 04/2018